

JOE ULYATT

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

26/03/1992

Q Berlin, Germany

+49 1525 627 3793

▼ joewhocodes@gmail.com

ioewhocodes.com

in linkedin/JoeWhoCodes

github/JoeDareZone

EDUCATION

2010 - 2013 SOUTHAMPTON UNIVERSITY

Bsc (Hons) Music Engineering

SKILLS

- React
- React Native
- Flutter
- Tailwind CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node.js
- Firebase
- Figma
- JEST

LANGUAGES

- English Native (C2)
- German Intermediate (B1)
- Spanish Intermediate (B1)

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in mobile development and using React Native, TypeScript, Node.js, JEST and Figma and 3 years experience React, JavaScript, CSS and HTML.

Spearheaded the launch of a fully-functional mobile application that secured over 40,000 active users within the first year.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JoeWhoCodes

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

Full Stack Mobile Developer

- Grew the app from launch to over 40,000 active users across 5 regions within the first year
- Ensured timely feature deployment and bug fixes, maintaining a 4.3star rating in the US
- Improved reliability through JEST and React Native Testing Library, achieving 99.97% crash-free sessions
- Contributed 7000+ commits, honing skills in React Native, TypeScript, Node.js & Firebase
- Revamped design and functionality through Figma & Tailwind.
 Streamlined user navigation leading to 25% reduction in bounce rates

100Devs

MAY 2022 - JUNE 2023

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with a team of 6 to build responsive web applications using React, TypeScript, and Node.js
- Developed full-stack applications with an average 95% code coverage with performance optimisations that reduced load times by 30%.
- Applied Agile methodologies (SCRUM) to ensure on-time project delivery, increasing team productivity by 15%.

JoeWhoCodes

MAY 2022 - JUNE 2023

Full Stack Web Developer

- Built full-stack web applications and static websites for 10+ small to medium-sized businesses.
- Consulted clients on SEO strategies and social media marketing, driving a 20% increase in online engagement.
- Delivered custom solutions for diverse industries, focusing on responsive design and performance